Only the strong will survive.
X-Men: Apocalypse is a action, adventure, science
fiction film directed by Bryan Singer.
After the re-emergence of the world's first mutant, world-destroyer
Apocalypse, the X-Men must unite to defeat his extinction level plan.
Professor Charles Xavier, played by James McAvoy.
Erik Lehnsherr / Magneto, played by Michael Fassbender.
Raven / Mystique, played by Jennifer Lawrence.
Hank McCoy / Beast, played by Nicholas Hoult.
En Sabah Nur / Apocalypse, played by Oscar Isaac.
Moira MacTaggert, played by Rose Byrne.
X-Men: Apocalypse is a 2016 American superhero film based on
the Marvel Comics superhero team the X-Men.
It is the ninth in the X-Men film series.
The film was directed by Bryan Singer, and written by Simon Kinberg, and stars James McAvoy, Michael Fassbender, Jennifer
Lawrence, Oscar Isaac, Nicholas Hoult, Rose Byrne, Tye Sheridan, Sophie Turner, Olivia Munn, and Lucas Till.
In the film, the ancient mutant En Sabah Nur / Apocalypse is inadvertently revived in 1983 and plans to recreate
the world in his own image, leading the X-Men to try to stop him and defeat his team of mutants.
The film was announced by Singer in December 2013, with Kinberg, Michael
Dougherty, and Dan Harris attached to develop the story.
Casting began in October 2014, while principal photography
commenced in April 2015 in Montreal and ended in August.
X-Men: Apocalypse premiered in London on May 9, 2016, and was released
in the United States on May 27 by 20th Century Fox.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $544 million.
A sequel, Dark Phoenix, was released in 2019.
The film explores themes of hero, superhero, mutant, based on comic, superhuman.
The tone is thought_provoking.